<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Recent Content on Ramblings of the 101st Monkey </title>
      <generator uri="https://hugo.spf13.com">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://blog.prohibitedgame.com/index.xml/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
    
    <updated>Wed, 11 Mar 2015 06:22:36 PDT</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>orientdb</title>
      <link>http://blog.prohibitedgame.com/post/orientdb/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2015 06:22:36 PDT</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.prohibitedgame.com/post/orientdb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There seems to be a never ending list of potential database solutions, each promising that they&amp;rsquo;re product will most definitely solve your needs better than all the other options out there.  Many try to sould like a silver bullet solution though they may try very hard to dance around those kinds of claims.
I was working on a solution where I felt a very good solution would be some combination of Neo4j (routing problems, and general graph modelling) and Mongo (just need some blobs for storing some blobs of map data).  I had also modeled a solution in Cassandra to substitution Mongo.  I liked the approach required to model things in Cassandra and enjoyed the reading I did to help me figure that all out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;INSERT LINKS&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did not have a favorable reaction to the
I was having a favorable reaction to Neo4j, though I had some issues with working through the limited master slave replication models but in general I felt I could make it all go.  The licensing was likely not to be a problem unless this project took off.   Though I wasn&amp;rsquo;t overly pleased with having to use two databases for the solution it seemed pretty common to use Neo4j with something else to get a full persistence model figured.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Investigating the tinkerpop and gremlin systems I stumbled across OrientDB as an alternative to Neo4j.  After some initial reading of the glossy material it seems like an real competitor for my Neo4j/Mongo architecture.   What I roughly needed was a graph database that I could occationaly store a blob in a property.   OrientDB sure seems to be exactly that.  I was also impressed with the class hierarchy and in dataspace I have a &amp;ldquo;content&amp;rdquo; driven class hierarchy so having a system that allows me to dynamically create a class hierarchy was a nice added bonus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ease of embedibility was also an added win.  I really want to have a very simple architecture and there are many situations that merit a lower latency than a round trip to an external DB would allow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using the Disruptor pattern in the action execution queue would benefit having in memory speeds to dereference the objects.  I suspect if introduced a network round trip that many of the benefits gained from the use of the Distruptor would be lost. There are many references and warning that introducing too much latency in the handling of the messages will occlude the speed gain from the Disruptor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hazelcast seems to be a perfect fit into OrientDB and intend to piggy pack on that mechnism to deal with routing of messages between servers.  The zero config features and easy of deploy are nice wins but the real win is the &amp;ldquo;magic&amp;rdquo; multi master replication it provides.   Reading up on Hazelcast its been founded by the old CTO of Terracotta which is good stuff and at one point was going to be my clustering solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point I only have some initial impression of the speed of OrientDB.  It seems very fast.  It initializes fast. It starts fast.  It inserts fast.   I haven&amp;rsquo;t exercised the clustering but I&amp;rsquo;m encouraged by what I&amp;rsquo;ve seen possible with Hazelcast and the rest of the OrientDB infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think I&amp;rsquo;ve watched most of the talks Luca Garulli has given, so much I barely hear his accent any more.  His English isn&amp;rsquo;t as bad as he says it is and you can tell it&amp;rsquo;s improved from some of the earliest interviews.  Most of those talks are excellent and are very inspiring seeing what he&amp;rsquo;s seemingly single handily did.  He always refers to a team etc. but it&amp;rsquo;s clear he&amp;rsquo;s written most of it himself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing that OrientDB seems to do better than Neo4j is the partitioning.   I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find support other them referring to partitioning as a very hard problem in the context of Neo4j while OrientDB gives you explicit control over which nodes can read and write to what partition.  All very cool.   The support for classes spanning partitions also useful it seems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got the Neo4j spatial extensions working after fighting some weird dependency problems (mostly my fault).  They seem to have a good implementation of an RTree in there and what seems like full support for OpenMaps data structures.   All very cool.  All very big.  All allot more than what I need.  All I really need is to be able to do the most basic queries of &amp;ldquo;what is in the rectangle&amp;rdquo;.  Guess what.  What&amp;rsquo;s the only thing that OrientDB currently supports?  Exactly that with a Lucene Spatial index.. ok then.. Nice and lean.  I&amp;rsquo;ve done some basic queries but I haven&amp;rsquo;t do a high scale test of it yet.   Initial tests are encouraging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luca Garulli answers the question &amp;ldquo;how fast is, does it scale, etc.&amp;rdquo; pretty well.  He basically says it&amp;rsquo;s very very fast (with a great italian accent) and from what I see it&amp;rsquo;s certainly true.  Poking around in the code he certainly understands what it is to write performant code and with the &amp;ldquo;new tech&amp;rdquo; the he created with the new indexing schemes sure seem to massively increase write speeds and insertion rates.  Again, I have yet to test at scale (another later post no doubt) but all the initial tests are good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lots of ways to interface to OrientDB.  The command line of course.  The excellent OrientDB Studio.  The gremlin console.  REST, Java API&amp;hellip; I must be missing something.  Point is it&amp;rsquo;s easy to call.  There is even a JDBC connector.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NoSQL DB has SQL support?  What?  can they do that?  do we need to name things different?  Perhaps.   A wise decision was made to &amp;ldquo;start&amp;rdquo; with SQL for the primary query language.  It&amp;rsquo;s a definite super set of SQL with some well thought through graph extensions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are even a few pages in the manual showing how to do things in Scala rather than Java which was encouraging given that&amp;rsquo;s how I&amp;rsquo;ll be calling it exclusively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OrientDB&amp;rsquo;s URI string is very convenient.  Allows for in memory databases that don&amp;rsquo;t persist or just any path.  I read somewhere that someone had thousands of databases on a single machine as well. Not that I plan to go that way but there are real scenarios for more than a single DB.  It&amp;rsquo;s good to see it doesn&amp;rsquo;t have that limitation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bad things to say about OrientDB.  Hmmm.. I normally wouldn&amp;rsquo;t consider a review complete without saying a few bad things but frankly I haven&amp;rsquo;t found anything of note to mention.  Granted I haven&amp;rsquo;t gotten it up to high scale yet with my data set but I&amp;rsquo;ll be testing it shorty.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>itSimple</title>
      <link>http://blog.prohibitedgame.com/post/new%20file/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2014 14:03:15 PST</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.prohibitedgame.com/post/new%20file/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;itSimple&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;itSimple is a very ambitious project to take the world of PDDL editors from basically simple text editing with nearly no error output other than failure or full solution.&lt;br /&gt;
Having fought writing PDDL over the years with no tools it was a welcome find.  Though skeptical of it&amp;rsquo;s ability to satisfy the claims it made I&amp;rsquo;m beginning to be a believer.&lt;br /&gt;
It DOES feel like the tool limits you with the expressiveness of PDDL, I&amp;rsquo;ve come to embrace the patterns it forces you to do. It&amp;rsquo;s certainly kept me out of trouble that I have historically gotten into.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;Multiple approached&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;itSimple allows you to express the same thing in many way that end up with effectively (or exactly) the same PDDL output.   The Finite State Machine metaphor the force you to work within is a good visual mapping to the model your working with.  The tool itself is rather buggy but I&amp;rsquo;ve learned to work around most of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t edit the XML file&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tempting as it may sound.  Editing the input file has yielded me some more capabilities but very quickly you break parts of the app that you&amp;rsquo;ll miss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_3&#34;&gt;OCML sucks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even when you manage to find the pdf file on the site and decode the inscrutable doc&amp;hellip; and work around the differences in the doc and the tool itself&amp;hellip; You end up wishing you could just write the PDDL that it generates and call it a day.
My approach has been one of a minimalist, use the few patterns I know that work and pretend that most don&amp;rsquo;t exists.   I&amp;rsquo;m reserved myself to being &amp;ldquo;stuck&amp;rdquo; in PDDL 2.1 but I can&amp;rsquo;t seem to find a stable enough planner for any of the structures beyond that so it&amp;rsquo;s I&amp;rsquo;m stuck for a few reasons.  Frankly I don&amp;rsquo;t feel that it&amp;rsquo;s a limitation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_4&#34;&gt;Static analysis beats soft constraints?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems I won&amp;rsquo;t be getting soft contraints so I&amp;rsquo;m going to play games with various cost functions and maybe even statically evaluate the plan after the fact if I need too.  It sure seems like that I&amp;rsquo;ll have to do that for that contraint satisfaction system anyway.. Since I&amp;rsquo;m computing multiple solutions anyway for finding the unique solutions so it&amp;rsquo;s not much of a leap to evaluate it&amp;rsquo;s cost at that point and see if that can be used to guide it&amp;hellip; or allow the user to select preferences that manifest as soft contraints&amp;hellip; Anyway.. should probably move that to a CSP entry&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>crashplan</title>
      <link>http://blog.prohibitedgame.com/post/crashplan/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2014 14:03:15 PST</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.prohibitedgame.com/post/crashplan/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux Sound</title>
      <link>http://blog.prohibitedgame.com/post/sound/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 06:47:59 PST</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.prohibitedgame.com/post/sound/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Linux handling of sound hardware/software has been nothing short of terrible.  I think it&amp;rsquo;s been a huge contributer to delaying desktop adoption of Linux and a huge personal annoyance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a non professional musican I want to do the basic use cases.  Do the basic 4 track exercises.  Record a few tracks until I like them.  Basic mixing. Basic effects. Setting up play along and practice tracks.  Nothing profound.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an audio snob I want good sounding intruments.  I&amp;rsquo;m not going to tolerate anything but an excellent piano sound. A reverb that sounds like your in a toilet paper roll isn&amp;rsquo;t going to fly either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note app let me down&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apparently I can&amp;rsquo;t scroll like you think in that app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;VST stack&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The easiest way I have found to get a decent sound stack working is to first add the kxstudio repositoroies.  At that point you can just&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;rdquo;&amp;rsquo;
apt-get install cadence dssi-vst low-latency-linux
&amp;ldquo;&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and I get pretty much what I need.
Need to test out the kxstudio defaults.. That apparently changes some important settings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the kxstudio repositories seem to have vastly more recent things all working together than other distro&amp;rsquo;s I&amp;rsquo;ve changed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once all the above installs and you reboot.  A bit of fiddling in the jack config and things seem to work out.   Cadence provides a good way to manage bridges etc if you need that.   I&amp;rsquo;ve only used the ALSA one a few times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;Catia&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is certinly my goto app for begining to diagnose.  I certibnly prefer that to the grid interface of Ardour and since it&amp;rsquo;s all jack it works out no matter where you change it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;VSTHost&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;seems to work better for me than festige did.  It could be just underlying versions of things but immediatly it seemed to respond better, load faster and I found a plugin that the images worked in while they didn&amp;rsquo;t using festige.  I haven&amp;rsquo;t tried to save or load state yet so I&amp;rsquo;ll have to reserve judgement&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;Session Management&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve seen many solutions out there and some might work for some people but I haven&amp;rsquo;t found something that really works for me. My mostly lame mostly works solution is to load all the VSTs I might need up front then load Ardour which wires up most everything provided it touches Ardour.. which may or may not be a good practice but it&amp;rsquo;s something doesn&amp;rsquo;t limit me much in my workflow so I generally do that.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sysadmin</title>
      <link>http://blog.prohibitedgame.com/post/admin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 06:28:44 PST</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.prohibitedgame.com/post/admin/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;Tools&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For many years I never bothered to learn anything about being an effective admin.  I rarely needed those skills and a would fumble my way through whatever the need was at the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using a detachable terminal like screen or &lt;a href=&#34;http://byobu.co/&#34;&gt;Byobu&lt;/a&gt; is a nescessity when managing remote servers. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NawuGmcvKus&#34;&gt;The Listen to Mozart while learning Byobo&lt;/a&gt; is a pleasant over view of what it can do if you haven&amp;rsquo;t tried.  For me this replaced many of my lame tricks and I&amp;rsquo;ve still know about half the keybinding I should.  If your still hacking away at a &amp;ldquo;classic&amp;rdquo; terminal, do youself a favor and upgrade.  I won&amp;rsquo;t tell you how long it took me to upgrade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;What is going on?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;Processors&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How often have you sat at a prompt wondering what the computer is doing.  The above has some rudimentary monitoring but often you need more.  Top is a good start &lt;a href=&#34;http://hisham.hm/htop/&#34;&gt;htop&lt;/a&gt; is better. Not as profound an upgrade as byobu is but still work a bump&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_3&#34;&gt;Networking&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As fun as vmstat 1 is you don&amp;rsquo;t get the actual picture, sure you know the lights are on but you have no idea what&amp;rsquo;s going on in the room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;toc_4&#34;&gt;Nethogs&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a good sense of the WHO of network usage &lt;a href=&#34;http://nethogs.sourceforge.net/&#34;&gt;nethogs&lt;/a&gt; is a quick way to see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;toc_5&#34;&gt;iptraf&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a quick look at the WHAT of network usage &lt;a href=&#34;http://iptraf.seul.org/&#34;&gt;iptraf&lt;/a&gt; does the trick.  Though not as big a beast as &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wireshark.org/&#34;&gt;wireshare&lt;/a&gt; it seems to answer most of the questions I see to have.  Granted I&amp;rsquo;m no networking guy but for getting a sense if things are working etc. it seems to do the trick&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_6&#34;&gt;Key Exchange&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is another thing I took way to long to mature at.  Yeah, I typed passwords longer than I should.  Do yourself a favor and setup keys&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_7&#34;&gt;LDD is your friend&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_8&#34;&gt;apt-files&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metal As a Service</title>
      <link>http://blog.prohibitedgame.com/post/maas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2014 15:15:20 PST</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.prohibitedgame.com/post/maas/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;Initial Impressions of MAAS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems pretty complete.  I&amp;rsquo;ve only focused on the mangement of virtual boxes current and that is obviously not its forte, though it seems rather suited to do that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;Hardware&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have some older hardware that I&amp;rsquo;ll try to PXE boot and wait on LAN.  Until I wake cold hardware I won&amp;rsquo;t feel like I&amp;rsquo;ve really done what it&amp;rsquo;s made for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;Juju Integration&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like the seemingly perfect integration with Juju, rather encouraging.  Though likely not where I&amp;rsquo;ll end up in the long run with my crazy hybrid environment.  I may have to give up on trying to spin up stuff locally and setup a Juju in manual mode for all the local stuff I will effectively leave on while maybe a separate reagion in Digital Ocean when any scale is needed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JuJu</title>
      <link>http://blog.prohibitedgame.com/post/juju/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2014 15:15:15 PST</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.prohibitedgame.com/post/juju/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;Juju&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This seems to be my solution for deployment and orchestration.  Their charm metaphor as about how I want to think about these components.  I really don&amp;rsquo;t want to work out any details about setting up logstash and geting the agents connected. Juju seems to give me the ability to config, monitor and manage the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;Visual Interface&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It sure looks cool.  I can&amp;rsquo;t seem to find it to be reliable to actual build things with.  Luckily I don&amp;rsquo;t seem to care at all about it.  I quickly wrote two different totaly different could configs.  One based on OpenStack and one that&amp;rsquo;s just a tomcat cluster behind HA Proxy.  The GUI is still very useful for visualizing etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;rdquo;&amp;rsquo;
put screen shot here
&amp;ldquo;&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>networking</title>
      <link>http://blog.prohibitedgame.com/post/networking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2014 15:15:05 PST</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.prohibitedgame.com/post/networking/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;Virtual Networking&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My basic problem is that I&amp;rsquo;m setting up a small private cloud using MAAS with mostly virtual machines attached.  I&amp;rsquo;d like to have multiple machines hosting multiple virtual networks of KVM machines.  All mananged with virt-manager.  I&amp;rsquo;m currently good at one machine I just have to figure out how to tunnel too or bridge .. or route.. or.. whatever network magic is missing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I intend to write about my solution here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quick update.. I hate networking.
A near solution I figured out is to have separate virtual networks running a few KVM based VMS on separate boxes.  Instead of running MAAS inside the internal network I run it with two network cards.  One real one wired into it&amp;rsquo;s own switch that some day will have some real hardware on it and a virtual network where the VMs live.   I then put a static route to each of the virtual networks (and physical) on the physical router that is the gateway for the MAAS controller and the rest of the host machines in the house.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automated Planning</title>
      <link>http://blog.prohibitedgame.com/post/pddl/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2014 22:31:54 PST</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.prohibitedgame.com/post/pddl/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;The attraction to a true declarative language&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was shocked how quickly one could start using PDDL. Since there are barely any keywords to know in the langauge the result is you can code as soon as you get the mechanism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;Finite State Machines&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using Finiste State Machines to model the behavior of the objects in the world and then using itSimple to generate PDDL via its internal XML representation allows you to not write the actions explicitly.  The practicle result is you have to be extremely aware of guard clauses and the like in the FSM and as part of debugging your constantly checking the generated conditions in the info box within the itSimple interface.  Also I seem to be checking the PDDL generated output tabs in itSimple as well when you have malformed precondtion or the like.  I&amp;rsquo;ve been stumped by many a (and ()) precondition or effect which doesn&amp;rsquo;t fly in most planners.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Motivation</title>
      <link>http://blog.prohibitedgame.com/post/why/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2014 21:57:33 PST</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.prohibitedgame.com/post/why/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At some point in many an engineers career they get lured into management.  It&amp;rsquo;s often seen as a good thing and there are many benefits to it and for the most part I don&amp;rsquo;t regret the path.  What I &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; miss is the making of things. The actual stacking of the blocks. The satisfaction of seeing the nicely stack of freshly chopped wood.  It&amp;rsquo;s a well documented thing that building something with your hands is satisfying.  Coding, though a bit more abstract, does have a similar satisfaction.  Seeing something &lt;em&gt;go&lt;/em&gt; that you wrote has a similar feel.  Not as rewarding but again more than you would think are unit tests and the like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Great &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=u6XAPnuFjJc&#34;&gt;Video&lt;/a&gt; on what motivates us and the improvement of ones abilities and knowledge.  I absolutly felt that pull into the field of computers.  It was a very clean way to make things.
When I first got pulled into managment I didn&amp;rsquo;t continue coding enough to scratch the itch and became unsettled by it.  I had a novel idea for a game engine to &amp;ldquo;fix&amp;rdquo; some of the micro managing nature of the early command and conquer style games that were just becoming popular in the late 90s.  So I went off to learn about graphics and automated planning and backend technologies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve had several stack changes over the years playing with these ideas. I had settled on a Google App Engine based stack before I found Scala, which caused me to rethink several things thought libGDX remained constant.   LibGDX doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to care to much (though the need for source for the GWT compile has by stymied for a but though there are some solutions in the works, I hope to not solve that problem and let others)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sweet Dreams of Scala</title>
      <link>http://blog.prohibitedgame.com/post/scala/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2014 21:45:37 PST</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.prohibitedgame.com/post/scala/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve always had an interest in programing languages.  We didn&amp;rsquo;t call them DSLs then but still liked how it made us think about things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A very wise programmer explained to me that laziness is an important virtue for a programmer.  Not in the sense of stuck on the couch but not doing things you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t. Automate taking out the proverbial trash.  Do less when that&amp;rsquo;s enough. Don&amp;rsquo;t over engineer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scala allows you to focus on the details and only on the details.  I had really resigned myself to Java without knowing.  I think I was in a longer honey moon off C++&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;is this how you do a block quote? yup!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still feel like a Java programmer writing Scala, though I occationally have an excellent function that reads like a real Scala dev.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;rdquo;&amp;rsquo;
insert a good gist here
&amp;ldquo;&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started</title>
      <link>http://blog.prohibitedgame.com/post/blogging/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2014 22:44:15 PST</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.prohibitedgame.com/post/blogging/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;So you want to blog?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well more like I need to do some writing.
I wanted something simple something I didn&amp;rsquo;t have to fight.  I just want a place to enter some text and it should look nice without some hassle making or hosting it.  This of course leads you to find all these fancy static site generators.   I was recommended &lt;a href=&#34;http://octopress.org/&#34;&gt;Octopress&lt;/a&gt; and quickly found lots of text that made it sounds all very wonderful.  I liked the range of templating capabilites.  Seemed to be designed for hackers etc&amp;hellip;  All good on paper and for many clearly capable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://jekyllrb.com/&#34;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; was my second choice and this was built on it so it must be wonderful, and I&amp;rsquo;m sure it is.  I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t know.
Let&amp;rsquo;s just say my first experience with Ruby wasn&amp;rsquo;t a pleasant one.  I&amp;rsquo;m the kind of guy that makes fun of Ruby.  I think this &lt;a href=&#34;http://codefol.io/posts/Why-Ruby-Should-Stay-a-Laughing-Stock&#34;&gt;guy&lt;/a&gt; has the right of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For some inexplicable reason I couldn&amp;rsquo;t get everything to install. Granted I didn&amp;rsquo;t try in any real &amp;ldquo;pull up the sleaves&amp;rdquo; kind of way, but the point of this project was to bet quick and easy.  I made a few stabs, tried a few different distro&amp;rsquo;s.  I got various inscrutible errors that didn&amp;rsquo;t result much from google.  Let&amp;rsquo;s go play with RVM yeah, that&amp;rsquo;ll be fun because what you need from your toy langauges is multiple versions &amp;ldquo;managed&amp;rdquo;.  Aren&amp;rsquo;t toy languages supposed to be easy and fun to setup?  Isn&amp;rsquo;t that half the appeal, low overhead and maintenance?  Aren&amp;rsquo;t the Ruby folk all &amp;ldquo;We don&amp;rsquo;t have these kinds of problems like the PHP folk!&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I should probably save bashing Ruby and other toy languages for a more in depth focused series of comments but for now I&amp;rsquo;d like to thank their gross inadequacies and the fine correlative capabilites of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.staticgen.com/&#34;&gt;staticgen&lt;/a&gt; because I started from the top and went until I found a real language.  Ohh look &lt;a href=&#34;https://golang.org/&#34;&gt;Go&lt;/a&gt; is a real language!  I think I&amp;rsquo;ll try &lt;a href=&#34;http://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; and sure enough within a few short minutes everything was working and I was picking themes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something tells me Hugo will be a tad faster than a Ruby Hello world&amp;hellip;. so far I haven&amp;rsquo;t seen it go over 25ms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a few more pages have been written.  I continue to be happy with Hugo and marvel at it&amp;rsquo;s speed. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t have  every bell and whistle as other system but my needs are simple and I have desired to fight those things.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Second Post</title>
      <link>http://blog.prohibitedgame.com/post/second/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2014 14:23:03 PST</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.prohibitedgame.com/post/second/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;testing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;tests 2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;test 1&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ipsum text! I like apples and banannas&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;This is a test of code insert

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a Gist!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src=&#34;https://gist.github.com/hhh42/5e2a6a06db5d4eff1517.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>http://blog.prohibitedgame.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2014 13:22:46 PST</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.prohibitedgame.com/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Test&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Blog Post</title>
      <link>http://blog.prohibitedgame.com/post/first/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2014 13:22:46 PST</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.prohibitedgame.com/post/first/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a test of some content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;foo&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>