<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Posts on Ramblings of the 101st Monkey </title>
      <generator uri="https://hugo.spf13.com">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://blog.prohibitedgame.com/post/index.xml/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
    
    <updated>Fri, 21 Nov 2014 22:31:54 PST</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automated Planning</title>
      <link>http://blog.prohibitedgame.com/post/pddl/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2014 22:31:54 PST</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.prohibitedgame.com/post/pddl/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The attraction to a true declarative language&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;test of a code block&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-go&#34;&gt;func (a PipeAddr) Network() string
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Motivation</title>
      <link>http://blog.prohibitedgame.com/post/why/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2014 21:57:33 PST</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.prohibitedgame.com/post/why/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At some point in many an engineers career they get lured into management.  It&amp;rsquo;s often seen as a good thing and there are many benefits to it and for the most part I don&amp;rsquo;t regret the path.  What I &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; miss is the making of things. The actual stacking of the blocks. The satisfaction of seeing the nicely stack of freshly chopped wood.  It&amp;rsquo;s a well documented thing that building something with your hands is satisfying.  Coding, though a bit more abstract, does have a similar satisfaction.  Seeing something &lt;em&gt;go&lt;/em&gt; that you wrote has a similar feel.  Not as rewarding but again more than you would think are unit tests and the like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Great &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=u6XAPnuFjJc&#34;&gt;Video&lt;/a&gt; on what motivates us and the improvement of ones abilities and knowledge.  I absolutly felt that pull into the field of computers.  It was a very clean way to make things.
When I first got pulled into managment I didn&amp;rsquo;t continue coding enough to scratch the itch and became unsettled by it.  I had a novel idea for a game engine to &amp;ldquo;fix&amp;rdquo; some of the micro managing nature of the early command and conquer style games that were just becoming popular in the late 90s.  So I went off to learn about graphics and automated planning and backend technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sweet Dreams of Scala</title>
      <link>http://blog.prohibitedgame.com/post/scala/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2014 21:45:37 PST</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.prohibitedgame.com/post/scala/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve always had an interest in programing languages.  We didn&amp;rsquo;t call them DSLs then but still liked how it made us think about things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A very wise programmer explained to me that laziness is an important virtue for a programmer.  Not in the sense of stuck on the couch but not doing things you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t. Automate taking out the proverbial trash.  Do less when that&amp;rsquo;s enough. Don&amp;rsquo;t over engineer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scala allows you to focus on the details and only on the details.  I had really resigned myself to Java without knowing.  I think I was in a longer honey moon off C++&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;is this how you do a block quote? yup!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started</title>
      <link>http://blog.prohibitedgame.com/post/blogging/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2014 22:44:15 PST</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.prohibitedgame.com/post/blogging/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;So you want to blog?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well more like I need to do some writing.
I wanted something simple something I didn&amp;rsquo;t have to fight.  I just want a place to enter some text and it should look nice without some hassle making or hosting it.  This of course leads you to find all these fancy static site generators.   I was recommended &lt;a href=&#34;http://octopress.org/&#34;&gt;Octopress&lt;/a&gt; and quickly found lots of text that made it sounds all very wonderful.  I liked the range of templating capabilites.  Seemed to be designed for hackers etc&amp;hellip;  All good on paper and for many clearly capable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://jekyllrb.com/&#34;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; was my second choice and this was built on it so it must be wonderful, and I&amp;rsquo;m sure it is.  I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t know.
Let&amp;rsquo;s just say my first experience with Ruby wasn&amp;rsquo;t a pleasant one.  I&amp;rsquo;m the kind of guy that makes fun of Ruby.  I think this &lt;a href=&#34;http://codefol.io/posts/Why-Ruby-Should-Stay-a-Laughing-Stock&#34;&gt;guy&lt;/a&gt; has the right of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For some inexplicable reason I couldn&amp;rsquo;t get everything to install. Granted I didn&amp;rsquo;t try in any real &amp;ldquo;pull up the sleaves&amp;rdquo; kind of way, but the point of this project was to bet quick and easy.  I made a few stabs, tried a few different distro&amp;rsquo;s.  I got various inscrutible errors that didn&amp;rsquo;t result much from google.  Let&amp;rsquo;s go play with RVM yeah, that&amp;rsquo;ll be fun because what you need from your toy langauges is multiple versions &amp;ldquo;managed&amp;rdquo;.  Aren&amp;rsquo;t toy languages supposed to be easy and fun to setup?  Isn&amp;rsquo;t that half the appeal, low overhead and maintenance?  Aren&amp;rsquo;t the Ruby folk all &amp;ldquo;We don&amp;rsquo;t have these kinds of problems like the PHP folk!&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I should probably save bashing Ruby and other toy languages for a more in depth focused series of comments but for now I&amp;rsquo;d like to thank their gross inadequacies and the fine correlative capabilites of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.staticgen.com/&#34;&gt;staticgen&lt;/a&gt; because I started from the top and went until I found a real language.  Ohh look &lt;a href=&#34;https://golang.org/&#34;&gt;Go&lt;/a&gt; is a real language!  I think I&amp;rsquo;ll try &lt;a href=&#34;http://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; and sure enough within a few short minutes everything was working and I was picking themes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something tells me Hugo will be a tad faster than a Ruby Hello world&amp;hellip;. so far I haven&amp;rsquo;t seen it go over 25ms.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Second Post</title>
      <link>http://blog.prohibitedgame.com/post/second/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2014 14:23:03 PST</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.prohibitedgame.com/post/second/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;testing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;tests 2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;test 1&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like apples and banannas&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;This is a test of code insert

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a Gist!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src=&#34;https://gist.github.com/hhh42/5e2a6a06db5d4eff1517.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;short gist ?
{{% gist 5e2a6a06db5d4eff1517 %}}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;maybe some html?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{{% highlight html %}}
    &lt;section id=&#34;main&#34;&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;h1 id=&#34;title&#34;&gt;{{ .Title }}&lt;/h1&gt;
    {{ range .Data.Pages }}
        {{ .Render &amp;ldquo;summary&amp;rdquo;}}
    {{ end }}
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
{{%/highlight%}}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go?
{{% highlight go %}} A bunch of code here {{%/highlight%}}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was supposed to be scala ?
{{% highlight scala %}}
class CSPResultConverter {
  def convert(assignment: Assignment): Set[TileInstance] = {
    //    val tileVariables: List[Variable] = for (foo &amp;lt;- assignment.getVariables.iterator()) yield foo
    (for (variable &amp;lt;- assignment.getVariables) yield {
      variable match {
        case tv: TileVariable =&amp;gt; new TileInstance(tv.tileSpot,
          forceTile(assignment.getAssignment(tv)))
        case _ =&amp;gt; {
          println(&amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s this case?&amp;rdquo;)
          TileInstance.noTile
        }
      }
    }).toSet&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;}
}
{{%/highlight%}}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{{ template &amp;ldquo;_internal/disqus.html&amp;rdquo; . }}&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Blog Post</title>
      <link>http://blog.prohibitedgame.com/post/first/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2014 13:22:46 PST</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.prohibitedgame.com/post/first/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a test of some content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;foo&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://blog.prohibitedgame.com/post/copy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.prohibitedgame.com/post/copy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;testing 3!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So you want to blog?  Well more like I need to do some writing.
I wanted something simple something I didn&amp;rsquo;t have to fight.  I just want a place to enter some text and it look nice without some hassle hosting it.  This of course leads you to find all these fancy static site generators.   I was recommended Octapres and quickly found lots of text that made it sounds all very wonderful.  I liked the range of templating capabilites.  Seemed to be designed for hackers etc.&lt;br /&gt;
Jekyl was my second choice and this was built on it so it must be wonderful, and I&amp;rsquo;m sure it is.  I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t know.&lt;br /&gt;
Let&amp;rsquo;s just say my first experience with Ruby wasn&amp;rsquo;t a pleasant one.  I&amp;rsquo;m the kind of guy that makes fun of Ruby.  For some inexplicable reason I couldn&amp;rsquo;t get everything to install. Granted I didn&amp;rsquo;t try in any real &amp;ldquo;pull up the sleaves&amp;rdquo; kind of way, but the point of this project was to bet quick and easy.  I made a few stabs, tried a few different distro&amp;rsquo;s.  I got various inscrutible errors that didn&amp;rsquo;t result much from google.  Let&amp;rsquo;s go play with RVM yeah, that&amp;rsquo;ll be fun because what you need from your toy langauges is multiple versions &amp;ldquo;managed&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>